Barbara Hernandez

Full Stack Software Engineer with over six years experience in technology. Experienced front end developer, comfortable with all front end frameworks. Methodical approach to Java or Node.js back end development, comfortable with relational and non-relational databases. An innovative thinker, capable of designing new applications or additions that integrate with existing technology. A team player who steps up to any challenge.

SKILLS

Java, Spring, Spring Boot, PWS, Jenkins, GIT (Source Control), REST, API, Express, SQL, MySQL, Firebase, MongoDB, Node.js, React, React Native, Angular, HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, Adobe Suite, SEO, and WordPress

EXPERIENCE

Cognizant - Associate Software Engineer

Atlanta, GA | NOVEMBER 2019 - PRESENT

- Developed additions to and maintained highly visible pages for an enterprise level e-commerce web application for a fortune 500 company with more than 55 million unique monthly visitors.
- Coordinated Agile workflow with local team and 3 additional teams in New York, San Francisco, and India.
- Assisted core team to begin transition of several small applications to Google Cloud from Heroku.
- Served as Tech Lead for a React Native POC with Firebase database demonstrating new features such as a shared shopping bag for ecommerce that would allow users to scan items in store and pay on their mobile device. This idea was pitched to Macy's and retained a white labeled POC within Cognizant.
- Contributed to Java based POCs with microservice architecture using Spring/Spring Boot to create the project and Jenkins and PWS for deployment.
- Managed Source Control for POC projects using GIT, supporting less experienced team members.
- Created documentation for new hires which reduced set-up time of the local environment from roughly one week to a single day.
- Participated with colleagues in the IBM Covid-19 Hackathon to create a MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) application to show COVID-19 data by state, with data pulled from an open source API, in a format that wouldn't intimidate or confuse, including IBM Watson chat client to provide further information and additional customizable widgets such as a feed of uplifting social posts via Instagram API.

Home Care Institute — Special Project Manager

John's Creek, GA | SEPTEMBER 2013 - MAY 2019

- Coordinated upgrades and maintenance of web applications with React based front-end and Java back-end.
- Trained over 100 clients to use beginner and advanced features of both web application and mobile application.
- Created and Maintained documentation for internal and client usage of an e-learning application with over 25,000 active users.

- Developed and Maintained all public-facing web applications using WordPress, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Implemented use of SCSS to streamline per-client customization of web applications.
- Cultivated client trust by providing reliable on-demand data reporting and high level technical support.
- Oversaw roll out of new communication software to increase speed of communication between team members and reduce the risk of lost or late response both internally and externally, as well as a new time tracking solution which saved hundreds of dollars per employee per year.

JET Programme — Assistant Language Teacher

Kamikitayama-mura, Japan | AUGUST 2012 - AUGUST 2013

EDUCATION

University of Georgia — A.B. Linguistics, A.B. Spanish Language & Literature

Athens, GA | AUGUST 2008 - MAY 2012

Graduated May 2012 Magna Cum Laude

Minor in Japanese Studies

Georgia Institute of Technology Professional Education — Certificate of Full Stack Web Development

Atlanta, GA | AUGUST 2018 - FEBRUARY 2019

This 6 month MERN stack focused program was taught by a working industry professional. In addition to technical skills the course focused on best practices, taking a project from idea through design and into production, and using version control to facilitate team work.

Georgia Institute of Technology Professional Education — Certificate of Accelerated Java Boot Camp

Atlanta, GA | August 2019 - October 2019

This accelerated boot camp was highly selective, only open to promising candidates of which only the top 25 were selected. Curriculum was designed to take developers from little to no Java Knowledge to fully qualified and ready to work on client projects in just 12 weeks of full time study. Graduates were eligible to interview with the sponsoring company.

I was one of only 16 to be offered a position from the sponsor.